<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/personal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2023-10-03T22:48:03+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/personal/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Data Storage Authority | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>A deep dive into data storage technology</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">About the Author</title>
      <link href="/about-the-author" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About the Author" />
      <published>2023-09-01T10:18:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2023-09-01T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/about-the-author</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/about-the-author">&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I’m Ricky Martin in my day job, I am the Director of Customer Advocacy and Strategic Trends at NetApp and I am committed to empowering our customers, partners, and stakeholders. My approach begins with active listening, enabling me to gain valuable insights into their unique needs and challenges. Leveraging my extensive experience, comprehensive research, and collaborations with industry leaders, I share invaluable insights that drive well-informed decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within NetApp, I hold a leadership role in the APAC region while also contributing to a broader global initiative. I work closely with our diverse customer base and collaborate seamlessly with cross-functional NetApp teams. My mission is to bridge the gap between business strategy and emerging technology trends. By remaining at the forefront of industry shifts and foreseeing emerging technologies, I equip NetApp’s stakeholders with the tools to align their strategies with the dynamic landscape of data-driven businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My passion lies in cultivating robust customer relationships, forging connections, and ensuring our strategies remain consistently current, relevant, and customer-centric. Together, we navigate the ever-evolving technology landscape to inspire innovation and drive success.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ricky Martin</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="personal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Hi there! I’m Ricky Martin in my day job, I am the Director of Customer Advocacy and Strategic Trends at NetApp and I am committed to empowering our customers, partners, and stakeholders. My approach begins with active listening, enabling me to gain valuable insights into their unique needs and challenges. Leveraging my extensive experience, comprehensive research, and collaborations with industry leaders, I share invaluable insights that drive well-informed decision-making.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
